Frederick G. Holland Company Records
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Frederick G. Holland Company Records.
undated, 1912-1959.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Holland, Frederick G.
13.75 linear feet.
MSS20050066
The collection contains financial records, legal documents, blueprints, drawings, newspaper clippings and photographs of the houses built by the Frederick G. Holland Company between 1923 and 1959. The houses were constructed primarily in a housing development in East Hartford, Connecticut, although additional properties in Bloomfield, Hartford, Wethersfield and South Windsor are included.
Biography
No biographical or historical information available for Mr. Holland or his company.
Scope and Content
The collection contains financial records, legal documents, blueprints, drawings, newspapers clippings and photos of the houses built by the Frederick G. Holland Company between 1923 and 1959. The houses were constructed primarily in a housing development in East Hartford, Connecticut, although additional properties in Bloomfield, Hartford, Wethersfield and South Windsor are included.
Arrangement
Series I: Construction Financial Records ( undated, 1923-1939 )
Series II: Legal Documents ( 1912-1959 )
Series III: Blueprints and Drawings ( undated, 1923-1948 )
Series IV: Ephemera and Artifacts ( undated, 1927-1937 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history and Connecticut business records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Holland, Frederick G.
Organizations:
Frederick G. Holland Company.
Places:
East Hartford (Conn.)
Subjects:
Building--Connecticut.; Construction contracts--Connecticut.; Building--Design and construction.; Housing--Connecticut--East Hartford.; Dwellings--Connecticut--Photographs.; East Hartford (Conn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.
Document Types:
Photographs.; Blueprints.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Drawings.; Contracts.; Newspapers.; Deeds.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Crawford Westbrook in 2005.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Construction Financial Records (all locations East Hartford, Connecticut, unless noted), undated, 1923-1939
  - 7 Alden St., 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 9 Alden St., 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 178 Ashley St., 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 358 Asylum St., 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 758 Asylum St., 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - "Bloomfield Job,", 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    See Folder 110
  - 32 Brewster St., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 236 Brewster St., 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 476 Brewster St., 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 489 Broad St., 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Burnham St. (unidentified), 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Capitol National Bank Building, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Carroll Rd. (unidentified), 1926-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 15 Carroll Rd. (Lot 9), 1927 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    See Folder 112
  - 48 Carroll Rd., 1925-1927 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    See Folder 114
  - 54 Carroll Rd., 1926-1928 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - 59 Carroll Rd., 1926-1927 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - 64 Carroll Rd., 1926-1931 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    See Folder 116
  - 81 Central Ave., 1938 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - 83 Central Ave., 1927 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Chapel St. (unidentified), undated, 1929-1938 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - 31 Chapel St., 1927 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - 91 Chapel St., 1927-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - 36 Chapman St., 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    See Folder 120
  - Clark St. (unidentified), 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Crosby St. (unidentified), 1931 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Edwards St. (unidentified), 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - 28 Ellridge St., 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Ellsworth St. (unidentified), undated, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - 7 Ellsworth St., 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    See Folder 124
  - 9 Ellsworth St., 1929-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - 17 Ellsworth St., 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - 20 Ellsworth St., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    See Folder 125
  - 22 Ellsworth St., 1930 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - 25 Ellsworth St., 1928 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - 27 Ellsworth St., 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
  - 28 Ellsworth St., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 37)
  - 29 Ellsworth St., 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - 30 Ellsworth St., 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - 31 Ellsworth St., 1928-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - 35 Ellsworth St., undated, 1929-1932 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    See Folder 126
  - 55 Elm St., 1929-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - 131 Elm St., 1930-1938 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - 50 Englewood Ave., Bloomfield, CT, 1934-1938 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - 150 Englewood Ave., Bloomfield, CT, 1928 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - 77 Ensign St., 1931-1939 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    See Folder 128
  - 405 Farmington Ave., 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - Filley St. (unidentified), 1927 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - 399 Forbes St., 1933 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    See Folder 129
  - 34 Fuller Ave., undated, 1934-1935 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    See Folder 159
  - 44 Garden St., 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - 202 Garden St., 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - 684 Main St., 1923 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - 948 Main St., 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
  - 1770 Main St., 1930-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 55)
  - 118 New Park Ave., 1928 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
  - 599 Nott Rd., Wethersfield, CT, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Oak St. (unidentified), 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
  - 50 Orchard St., 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
  - 783 Park St., 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
  - Prospect St. (unidentified), 1927-1932 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - St. John's Church Recreation Hall, 1927 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - 64 Saunders St., 1934-1939 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - 74 Saunders St., undated, 1927-1928 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - 4-6 Sherman Ave., 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
  - 398 Silver Ln., 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
  - 1177 Silver Ln., 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
  - 82 South Prospect Ave., 1926-1928 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
  - 100 South Prospect Ave., 1927-1928 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
  - Springfield and Ellington Rds, South Windsor, CT, 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
  - Summer Ridge Country Club, 1933-1934 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
  - 45 Tower Rd., 1927-1928 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
  - Tower Rd. (unidentified), undated, 1927 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
  - 96 Tunxis Ave., Bloomfield, CT, 1933-4 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - 54 Vernon St., undated (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - 88 Vine St., 1938 (Box 2:, Folder 76)
  - 30 Walters Pl., 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 77)
  - 15 Wells Ave., 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
  - 35 Wells Ave., 1928-1929 (Box 2:, Folder 79)
  - 967 West Blvd., 1933 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
  - 117 Westphal Ave., 1928 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
  - 159 Wethersfield Ave., Hartford, CT, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 82)
  - 254 Wethersfield Ave., Hartford, CT (Box 2:, Folder 83)
  - 730 Wetherfield Ave., 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
- Series II: Legal Documents, 1923-1959
  - Deeds and Morgages, 1912-1959 (Box 3)
- Series III: Blueprints and Drawings, undated, 1923-1948
  - 7 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 85)
  - 8 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 86)
  - 24 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 87)
  - 30 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 88)
  - 31 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 89)
  - 36 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 90)
  - 37 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 91)
  - 42 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 92)
  - 49 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 93)
  - 54 Birchwood Rd., 1938 (Box OS:, Folder 94)
  - 55 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 95)
  - 60 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 96)
  - 61 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 97)
  - 66 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 98)
  - 67 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 99)
  - 72 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 100)
  - 73 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 101)
  - 78 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 102)
  - 79 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 103)
  - 84 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 104)
  - 90 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 105)
  - 96 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 106)
  - 102 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 107)
  - 112 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 108)
  - 124 Birchwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 109)
  - "Bloomfield Job,", 1933 (Box OS:, Folder 110)
    See Folder 6
  - 476 Brewer St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 111)
  - 15 Carroll Rd., 1926 (Box OS:, Folder 112)
    See Folder 14
  - 28 Carroll Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 113)
  - 48 Carroll Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 114)
    See Folder 15
  - 53 Carroll Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 115)
  - 64 Carroll Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 116)
    See folder 18
  - 64 Central Ave., undated (Box OS:, Folder 117)
  - 23 Chapel St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 118)
  - 89 Chapel St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 119)
  - 36 Chapman St., 1929 (Box OS:, Folder 120)
    See Folder 24
  - Cobb Rd. unidentified, undated (Box OS:, Folder 121)
  - 16 Cobb Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 122)
  - East Hartford Chamber of Commerce Industrial Exhibit, 1928 (Box OS:, Folder 123)
  - 7 Ellsworth St., 1928 (Box OS:, Folder 124)
    See Folder 30
  - 20 Ellsworth St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 125)
    See Folder 33
  - 35 Ellsworth St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 126)
    See Folder 41
  - 55 Elmer St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 127)
  - 77 Ensign St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 128)
    See Folder 46
  - 399 Forbes St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 129)
    See Folder 49
  - 166 Holland Ln., undated (Box OS:, Folder 130)
  - 169 Holland Ln., 1941 (Box OS:, Folder 131)
  - 15 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 132)
  - 19 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 133)
  - 49 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 134)
  - 55 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 135)
  - 55 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 136)
  - 79 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 137)
  - 85 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 138)
  - 99 Knollwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 139)
  - 1770 Main St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 140)
  - Millwood Rd. unidentified, undated (Box OS:, Folder 141)
  - 104 Millwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 142)
  - 114 Millwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 143)
  - 124 Millwood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 144)
  - 599 Nott St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 145)
  - "Prospect St. or Carroll St.,", 1926 (Box OS:, Folder 146)
  - 60 Ridgewood Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 147)
  - St. John's Church Recreation Hall, 1927 (Box OS:, Folder 148)
  - 74 Saunders St., undated (Box OS:, Folder 149)
  - 1155 Silver Ln., undated (Box OS:, Folder 150)
  - 1170 Silver Ln., undated (Box OS:, Folder 151)
  - 82 South Prospect St., 1926 (Box OS:, Folder 152)
  - 100 South Prospect St., 1927 (Box OS:, Folder 153)
  - 45 Tower Rd., 1927 (Box OS:, Folder 154)
  - 15 Wells Ave., undated (Box OS:, Folder 155)
  - 117 Westphal Ave., undated (Box OS:, Folder 156)
  - 20 Wind Rd., undated (Box OS:, Folder 157)
  - [unidentified], "December House of the Month,", undated (Box OS:, Folder 158)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 159)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 160)
  - [unidentified], undated, 1948 (Box OS:, Folder 161)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 162)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 163)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 164)
  - [unidentified], 1923 (Box OS:, Folder 165)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 166)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 167)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 168)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 169)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 170)
  - [unidentified], 1936 (Box OS:, Folder 171)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 172)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 173)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 174)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 175)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 176)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 177)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 178)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 179)
  - [unidentified], undated (Box OS:, Folder 180)
  - Revised map of Sunset Estates, 1939 (Box OS)
  - East Hartford Street map, undated (Box OS)
  - Record book that corresponds with properties on Sunset Estates map, undated (Box OS)
- Series IV: Ephemera and Artifacts, undated, 1927-1937
  - Newspaper clippings, 1937 (Box 4:, Folder 181)
  - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box 4:, Folder 182)
    Photograph and negative of house at 34 Fuller Ave.
    See Folder 50
  - 4 copperplate halftones, prints and receipt, undated, 1927 (Box 4:, Folder 183)
  - Biography and photo of Frederick G. Holland, undated (Box 4:, Folder 184)
  - List of properties built, undated (Box 4:, Folder 185)